Finding aid for George William Cushing Papers and sound recordings, 1942-1955
Bentley Historical Library
George William Cushing papers and sound recordings
1942-1955
Bentley Historical Library
Cushing, George William, 1888-1968
851077 Aa 2
1.3 linear feet
230 audiotapes (in 9 boxes)
260 GB (online)
News editor and vice president of Detroit, Michigan, radio station, WJR, moderator of radio program, "In Our Opinion". Correspondence, radio transcripts, scrapbooks, broadcast discs, and audio-tapes of discs; include material concerning career of Senator Arthur H. Vandenberg, the senatorial campaign of 1942 between Prentiss Brown and Homer Ferguson, and radio broadcasting in general.
The collection was received from George Cushing (donor no. 3137 ) in 1955.
No further additions to the collection is expected.
The collection is open to research.
The collection contains audio tapes from which digital copies have been made. Source tapes are for staff use only. Audio files are only available in the Bentley Historical Library reading room on designated Bentley Library computers.
Digitization: The Library has undertaken the digitization of a number of sound recordings within this collection. The resulting audio files are available for playback only in the Bentley Library Reading Room. Links to item images and additional information are available within this finding aid. Original sound recordings are only available for staff use.
George W. Cushing, was born in Brighton, Michigan on November 25, 1888. In his career, he was both an advertising executive and a newsman. In 1909 he became a reporter on the Detroit News, also working while there in various editorial capacities. In 1912, he joined the Detroit office of the Taylor-Critchfield Advertising Agency; in 1914 he became first editor of the weekly publication of the Detroit Board of Commerce, The Detroiter.
In late 1915, Cushing was made advertising manager of the Federal Motor Truck Company, leaving here to join the Hudson Motor Car Company as advertising manager. He next helped to form the advertising agency of McKinney, Marsh and Cushing which handled advertising for the Ford Motor Company. After this he became first advertising director for the Graham-Paige Motors Corporation. He left this to become Detroit manager of Cosmopolitan Magazine for six years, and after that he was selected chief of information of the National Highway's Users Conference.
Cushing returned to Detroit in 1941 to join WJR as news editor and vice president. In 1942, he became moderator of "In Our Opinion" a weekly radio news program. He was assisted on many of the programs by regular panelists Detroit Free Press staff writers and columnists Adrian Fuller, Royce Howes, and William Coughlin. The program aired from 1942 to 1955 when Cushing retired. All together, he moderated 641 broadcasts, interviewing such guests as Senators Arthur Vandenberg and Homer Ferguson, Detroit Mayor Edward Jeffries.
In November 1954, Cushing began another series of program entitled "World Neighbors" which overlapped with "In Our Opinion" for a year.
The Cushing collection consists largely of sound recordings of a selection of the "In Our Opinion" radio program. There are also additional textual materials: clippings and other documents pertaining to the program and some transcriptions of particular programs.
The sound recordings of the "In Our Opinion" program were originally phonograph transmission discs. Nearly impossible to listen to because of their oversize format and the absence of appropriate players, the library applied for and received a grant in 1977 from the NHPRC to transfer a selection of the more than 600 discs onto reel-to-reel tapes. Many of the discs already showed signs of deterioration. The selection of what discs to preserve was based on the significance of the topics discussed and the importance of the interviewees. Among the guests were Senators Arthur Vandenberg and Homer Ferguson, automobile executive (later governor) George Romney, Congressman George Dondero, military historian General S.L.A. Marshall, political science Professor James K, Pollock, Governor Kim Sigler, Lowell Thomas, Thor Heyerdahl, Edward R. Murrow, and Episcopal Bishop Richard S. Emrich, among many others. Topics ranged from state and national politics, the impact of the war, foreign affairs, post-war re-conversion of the economy, and issues specific to Detroit and Michigan.
Detroit (Mich.); Journalists -- Michigan -- Detroit.; Radio broadcasting -- Michigan -- Detroit.; Detroit (Mich.) -- History.; Scrapbooks.; Sound recordings.; Brown, Prentiss M. (Prentiss Marsh), 1889-1973.; Cushing, George William, 1888-1968.; Ferguson, Homer, 1889-1982.; United States. Congress -- Elections, 1942.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.; WJR (Radio station: Detroit, Mich.); United States. Congress -- Elections, 1942.; WJR (Radio station: Detroit, Mich.); Cushing, George William, 1888-1968.; Brown, Prentiss M. (Prentiss Marsh), 1889-1973.; Dodero, George Anthony, 1883-1968.; Emrich, Richard S. M. (Richard Stanley Merrill), 1910-; Ferguson, Homer, 1888-1982.; Heyerdahl, Thor.; Marshall, S. L. A. (Samuel Lyman Atwood), 1900-1977.; Murrow, Edward R.; Pollock, James K. (James Kerr), 1898-1968.; Romney, George W., 1907-1995.; Sigler, Kim, 1894-; Thomas, Lowell, 1892-1981.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.
- Personal and Professional Papers
  - Biographical sketch (Box 1)
  - Arthur H. Vandenberg and his appearances on the radio, 1945-1952 (Box 1)
  - Religious program "Guide Waves", 1953 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence regarding program, "World Neighbors", 1952-1954 (Box 1)
  - Letters received upon occasion of his retirement, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Manuscripts of "In Our Opinion" programs (Box 1)
  - Typescripts of "In Our Opinion" programs, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Newspaper accounts and other material relating to "In Our Opinion" programs, 1942-1950; 4 volumes, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Newspaper accounts of the Prentiss Brown-Homer Ferguson Senatorial debate, October 25, 1942 (Box 2)
  - Newspaper accounts of the two income tax programs, February 27, 1944; March 5, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook containing teletype news releases of historical events (Box 2)
- In Our Opinion: recordings of programs, 7 in. reel-to-reel tapes; 7 1/2 ips
  [Digitized audio files are only available in the Bentley Historical Library reading room on designated Bentley Library computers.]
  - 1942
    - "The Defense of America from her Enemies Within", February 1, 1942 (Box 3)
      (Guest: John S. Bugas (Detroit Chief of the Federal Bureau of Investigation))
      (transcript of program in box 1)
    - "America's Attitude Toward the War", February 8, 1942 (Box 3)
      (Guest: Mayor Edward J. Jeffries, Jr. (Detroit))
    - "Mobilization of Manpower", April 26, 1942 (Box 3)
      (Guests: Hon. Paul V. McNutt (Chairman W.M.C.), Wendell Lund (Director of Mich. Unemployment Com.))
      (The surface of the disc from which this tape was made was poor)
    - China Plight, 1942 July 05; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 3)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-4-1]; (In Our Opinion forum featuring Miss Josephine A. Brown (Chung King), Chishau Lee (Vice-Consul General, Chicago), Professor Alfred H. Kelly (Wayne University), George W. Cushing (WJR))
    - The Doctor's Role in the War, 1942 July 19; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 3)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-5-1]; (In Our Opinion radio show featuring Lieutenant Colonel John G. Slevin (Surgeon General's Office), Dr. C. D. Moll (Chairman, Wayne Co., P.A.A.), George W. Cushing (WJR).)
    - Should Prisoners be Permitted to Join Armed Forces, 1942 July 26; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 3)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-6-1]; (In Our Opinion radio show featuring Dr. Garrett Heyns (Dir. State Corrections Comm.), Warden Joel R. Moore (Ionia Reformatory), George W. Cushing (WJR).)
    - "The Ferguson-Brown Debate", October 25, 1942 (Box 3)
      (Guests: Judge Homer Ferguson, Senator Prentiss M. Brown)
      (The program was originally one hour, but much is unusable due to damage to the transcription discs)
  - 1943
    - Monthly Cracker Barrel, 1943 March 07; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 3)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-8-1]; (In Our Opinion radio show featuring Professor Alfred H. Kelly (Wayne University), William Coughlin (Detroit Free Press), Duncan Moore (WJR), George W. Cushing (WJR).)
    - Percy Jones General Hospital, Battle Creek, 1943 March 14; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 3)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-9-1]; (Percy Jones General Hospital, Battle Creek (Guests: Private Ralph Alvarado (Pfc.), Robert W. Baird (Pfc.), Jack S. Field (1st Lt.), Lakin Bowman (2nd Lt.), John J. Kelley, Jr. (Captain), Helena Clearwater (Captain))
    - War Housing Problems, 1943 July 18; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 3)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-10-1]; (Guests: Charles F. Edgecomb (Secretary, Detroit Housing Commission), Sherwood L. Reeder (Director, Federal Housing Authority), James E. Atkinson (President, Michigan Real Estate Association))
    - Washington Newspaper Representatives at Mackinac Is, 1943 September 05; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 3)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-11-1]; (Tape 1; Guests: Raymond P. Brandt (St. Louis Post Dispatch), Esther Van Wagoner Tufty, Roscoe Drummond (Christian Science Monitor), Clifford Prevost (Free Press), Theodore C. Alford (Kansas City Star), Turner Catledge (New York Times))
    - Washington Newspaper Representatives at Mackinac Is, 1943 September 05; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 3)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-12-1]; (Tape 2; Guests: Raymond P. Brandt (St. Louis Post Dispatch), Esther Van Wagoner Tufty, Roscoe Drummond (Christian Science Monitor), Clifford Prevost (Free Press), Theodore C. Alford (Kansas City Star), Turner Catledge (New York Times))
    - Should Women Be Drafted?, 1943 September 12; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 3)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-13-1]; (Guests: Mrs. Sprague Holden, Ruth Crane, Miss Marge Daugherty, Helen Bauer.)
    - Detroit's Part in the War Since Pearl Harbor, 1943 December 05; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 3)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-14-1]; (Guests: George Romney (Automotive Council for War Production), Harvey Campbell (Detroit Board of Commerce).)
  - 1944
    - "Juvenile Delinquency", March 19, 1944 (Box 3)
      (Guests: Rev. Father Flanagan (Boy's Town), Judge Paul W. Alexander)
    - Influence of Music, 1944 August 13; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 3)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-17-1]; (Guests: Merle Evans and Beverly Kelley (Ringling Bros.), Valter Poole (Detroit Symphony Conductor), Graham Overgard (Band Conductor), Ozzie Nelson)
    - "Influence of Music", August 13, 1944 (Box 3)
      (Merle Evans and Beverly Kelley (Ringling Bros.), Valter Poole (Detroit Symphony Conductor), Graham Overgard (Band Conductor), Ozzie Nelson)
    - "Reconversion Problem" (Detroit and Washington)., August 27, 1944 (Box 3)
      (Guests: Senator Homer Ferguson; Senator Carl Hatch, Representative George Dondero (At Detroit), George Romney)
      (The surface of the original disc was bad)
    - Brazzaville Radio Station, 1944 September 03; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 3)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-19-1]; (Guests: Miss Helen Scott)
    - "Army Training in Schools", September 10, 1944 (Box 3)
      (Guests: Dr. David D. Henry (Wayne University), Dr. Eugene B. Elliott (Supt. Of Public Instruction))
      (The surface of the second half of the original disc was bad)
    - Historians' Job in This War, 1944 September 24; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 3)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-21-1]; (Guests: Milo F. Quaife, Dr. F. Clever Bald, Thomas I. Starr, Robert H. Larson.)
    - Problem of Automobile Parts, 1944 October 15; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 3)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-22-1]; (Guests: Major Samuel Pace, George Otto, Ed Moore.)
    - Moral Issues of America, 1944 November 05; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 3)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-23-1]; (Guests: Reverend G. Paul Musselman, B. E. Hutchinson, Dr. David Henry.)
    - Women Give Peace Views, 1944 November 12; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 3)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-24-1]; (Guests: Mrs. John Orman, Mrs. Marian James, Mrs. Donald McGuire, Mrs. Bruce Douglas, Mrs. Eugene Woodruff.)
    - Should We Have Compulsory Military Training?, 1944 November 26; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 3)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-25-1]; (Guests: Dr. John Hannah, Warren Bow, Col. Owen Cleary, Rev. T. T. Brumbaugh.)
    - The Bombing of Tokyo, 1944 December 03; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 3)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-26-1]; (Guests: "Singapore Joe" Fisher, Reverend Father Edmund Horne.)
    - Naval Warfare, 1944 December 10; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 3)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-27-1]; (Guests: Lieutenant John A. Walsh, Lieutenant Commander D. McCowen, Leon Coulter; 1st Class Machinist Mate.)
    - Michigan's Aviation Program: The Future of Air Travel, 1944 December 17; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 3)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-28-1]; (Guests: Maj. S.B. Steers, Manfred Burleigh, Allen Dean, William M. Packard; The Future of Air Travel.)
    - New Year's Resolutions, 1944 December 31; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 3)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-29-1]; (Guests: Edgar A. Guest, Malcolm Bingay)
  - 1945
    - No-Strike Pledge, 1945 January 07; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 3)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-30-1]; (Guests: August Scholle, W. T. Grant, Jess Ferrazza, Larry Yost)
    - Eisenhower Group, 1945 January 14; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 3)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-31-1]; (Ammunition Rationing, Guests: Captain Robert B. Olson, Private First Class Sidney S. Winborne, Private First Class Frank C. Hall, Private First Class. Virgil O. Barnes, Corporal Frank Christopian.)
    - "Our Foreign Policies", January 21, 1945 (Box 3)
      (Guests: Senator Vandenberg)
    - "Work or Fight", January 28, 1945 (Box 3)
      (Guests: Harvey Campbell, Victor Reuther, Edward L. Cushman, John L. Lovett)
      (large portions missing due to broken discs)
    - "Detroit Strikes", March 4, 1945 (Box 4)
      (Guests: Under Secretary of War Robert P. Patterson, S/SGT. Odell Cassada, Sgt. Elmer K. Forrest)
      (first transcription disc was broken-approx. 8 min. missing from 2nd quarter of program)
    - Factories Can't Employ Everybody, 1945 March 11; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-35-1]; (On the subject of Post-war employment, guests: C. Hartley Grattan, Robert F. C. Copeland.)
    - Red Cross, 1945 March 25; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-36-1]; (Guests: Flint, Michigan, Lansing, Michigan, Port Huron, Michigan, Detroit, Michigan)
    - Religion in the Lives of Front Line Fighters, 1945 April 01; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-37-1]; (Guests: Rev. W. Vine Russell, Chaplain W. F. Burke, Chaplain R. Talbot Watkins, Staff Sergeant J.K. Brentford, Sergeant H. T. Eufill, Reverend Father Joseph E. Whelan.)
    - Back-to-the-Farm Move, 1945 April 08; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-38-1]; (Guests: Harold Titus, Dean Samuel T. Dana, Professor Kenneth C. McMurry.)
    - Reich Occupation, 1945 April 15; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-39-1]; (Reich Occupation and Franklin Roosevelt Burial; Guests: Jack Bell)
    - San Francisco Conference, 1945 April 22; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-40-1]; (Guests: Senator Homer Ferguson, Senator Forrest C. Donnell.)
    - Detroit's Job After V-E Day, 1945 May 06; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-41-1]; (Guests: Senator Homer Ferguson, Rear Adm. M.F. Schoeffel, Col. Raymond J. Kelly.)
    - Women's Role in Future, 1945 May 13; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-42-1]; (Mother's Day at War; Guests: Dr. Helen Reed, Bertha Lutz, Mrs. A. G. Skard, Mrs. Esther Van Wagoner Tufty, J. D. Callaghan)
    - Nazi Brutality, 1945 May 20; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-43-1]; (Guests: Malcolm Bingay)
    - Survivors of USS Franklin, 1945 May 27; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-44-1]; (Guests: Lt. Gordon Hassig, Machinists Mate George Phillips, Seaman Robert L. Tice, Coxswain Gerald Astourian.)
    - Food Problem in Detroit, 1945 June 03; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-45-1]; (Part 1; Food Shortages and the OPA; Guests: Mrs. Walter K. Frost, Jimmie Asher, H.H. Varney, Owen Richards.)
    - Food Problem in Detroit, 1945 June 10; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-46-1]; (Part 2, Food Shortages; Guests: Walter Carven, Mrs. George Ghere, George Thierwechter, Bliss Bowman, Jimmie Asher, Marshall Wells.)
    - Ball-Burton-Hatch Labor Bill, 1945 June 24; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-47-1]; (On the Labor Relations Act. Guests: Senator Joseph H. Ball, Senator Carl A. Hatch, Senator Harold H. Burton, Donald Richberg, Senator Homer Ferguson.)
    - Governor's Conference (Mackinac Island), 1945 July 01; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-48-1]; (Guests: Governor Harry F. Kelly, Governor Herbert B. Maw, Governor Earl Warren, Governor Ellis Arnall, Governor Raymond E. Baldwin, James Haswell.)
    - Reconversion, 1945 September 02; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-49-1]; (V-J Day; Guests: C E. Wilson, Senator Homer Ferguson, John A. Fry, Leo Donovan.)
    - Government's Views on Reconversion, 1945 September 09; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-50-1]; (Guests: Louis C. Miriani, George Bowles, Arthur O'Shea.)
    - How Should We Treat the Japs?, 1945 September 16; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-51-1]; (Guests: Dr. Thoburn T. Brumbaugh, James R. Young, J. B. Powell, Adrian Fuller.)
    - Post-War Conditions in Europe, 1945 September 30; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-52-1]; (Guests: Congressman Chester E. Merrow, Congressman George A. Dondero, Congressman Bartel J. Jonkman, B. Dale Davis.)
    - State Editors' Views on Truman's First Six Months, 1945 November 04; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-53-1]; (Guests: Nelson Brown, Harry E. Whitely, Webb McCall, Merle H. Dafoe, Owen C. Deatrick; Broadcast from Mason, Michigan.)
    - Military Training for Peacetime American Youth, 1945 November 11; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-54-1]; (Guests: Colonel Dunlap C. Clark, Mrs. Lula E. Bachman, Reverend William J. Miller, Mrs. John K. Ormond, John Bethurum.)
    - President Truman's Proposed Health Bill, 1945 November 25; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-55-1]; (Tape 1; Guests: Dr. George I. McLellan, Rep. John Dingell, Nelson Cruikshank, Dr. Howard Schriver.)
    - President Truman's Proposed Health Bill, 1945 December 02; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-56-1]; (Tape 2; Guests: Arthur P. Johnson, Rep. John Dingell, Nelson Cruikshank, Dr. George I. McLellan.)
    - General Public on Truman's Proposed Health Bill, 1945 December 16; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-57-1]; (Tape 3; Guests: Leonard G. Bradley, Cleveland Lowry, John Stevenson, Mrs. Sidney Marwill, Henry J. Beyerle, Nicholas J. Schorn, Elizabeth Coulson.)
  - 1946 (Box 4)
    - Air Future of Detroit and Michigan, 1946 January 13; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-58-1]; (Aviation and the individual; Guests: Col. Thomas G. Lamphier, Col. Floyd Evans, William A. Mara, Joseph W. Hance, Marc Williams, Curtis Haseltine.)
    - Does Michigan Need a Capital Punishment Law?, 1946 February 03; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-59-1]; (Guests: Joseph E. Warner, Joel R. Moore, Louis B. Seltzer, Frank T. Cullitan.)
    - Food Problem in Europe, 1946 March 17; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-60-1]; (Prevention of World Food Shortage; Guests: Senator Homer Ferguson, Alfred D. Stedman, Fred A. Motz.)
    - "Price Control", March 24, 1946 (Box 4)
      (Guests: Mrs. John W. Griffen, Mrs. A. C. Hughes, Frank X. Martel, Roy Robinson, Leo Donovan)
      (Bad cracks in first disc made part of program unplayable)
    - Food Problems, 1946 March 31; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-62-1]; (Why a food shortage?; Guests: Dr. Ernest L. Anthony, Miss Winning S. Pendergast, John W. Piercey, Edward J. Frawley, John Frederick Muelh.)
    - Time Change, 1946 April 07; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-63-1]; (Guests: Mrs. Guy Bedell, William L. Favinger, Charles Boyd, Chester Culver, John Considine, Sid Easton, M. W. Wisely, E.I. Besemer, August Scholle.)
    - Salvation Army, 1946 April 21; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-64-1]; (Guests: Captain Tom Crocker, Maj. Mrs. Oscar Agre, Maurice McGriffin, George Clutter, Arthur Truesdale.)
    - "A Decade of Decision", May 5, 1946 (Box 4)
      (Guests: Eric A. Johnston (President of the U.S. Chamber of Commerce)
    - What Mothers Are Worrying About, 1946 May 12; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-66-1]; (Guests: Louis Charbonneau, Sally Pickens, Patricia Hayes, Charles Anthony Jr.)
    - I Am An American Day, 1946 May 19; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-67-1]; (Guests: John Panchuk, Joseph Karasiewicz, Rudolph Herman, H.S. Derderian.)
    - Significance of the Golden Jubilee (of the Automobile), 1946 May 26; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 4)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-68-1]; (Part 1; Guests: Lt. Gen. William S. Knudsen, George Romney, Prentiss M. Brown, William E. Stirton, Leo Donovan.)
    - Senator Arthur Vandenberg, 1946 June 02; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 5)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-69-1]; (Check content. Original listing of discs for Jan 2, 1946 is titled The Man with the Dinner Pail. Seems to be Sen. Vanderberg's monthly appearance on the show. See paper Finding Aid & transcripts)
    - Golden Jubilee (of the automobile), 1946 June 02; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips (Box 5)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-291-1]; (Part)
    - Father's Day, 1946 June 16; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 5)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-71-1]; (Guests: Arthur Crampton, W. H. Hefelfinger, Bruce Tallman, Bruce McKay, Hugh McKay, Doyle Stemen, Carlos Stemen, Wm. Pittsley, Chas Pittsley, Arthur Crampton Jr.)
    - Controversial Problems of Youth, 1946 June 23; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 5)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-72-1]; (Guests: David Anderson, Robert Neale, Robert Halbrook, Robert Baker, Bertrand Sandweiss, James Maynard.)
    - KAPPA Delegates Discuss OPA, 1946 June 30; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 5)
      - [Part 1], [851077-SR-73-1]; (Guests: Nora Waln, Mrs. Gustave M. Heiss, Pattie Field O'Brien, Roxanna Jackson, Helen Bower.)
    - OPA, 1946 July 07; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 ½ ips (Box 5)